# James Harmer

# UX/UI Designer

#### View my portfolio

I have been working as a designer since 2014. Starting out as an apprentice, I learned my trade working for a small agency, gaining experience and a qualification in Graphic Design. Over the last 9 years I have progressed and honed my skills to specialise in UX and UI Design.

I am a quick learner with good communication skills and an eye for design and detail. I have experience working with UX and UI principles to deliver intuitive designs that people love to use and meet the goals of the business. I am looking for the opportunity to improve my skills and work within a dynamic company to further develop my career as a Product Designer.

## Work Experience

#### Web Design Assistant Manager - Search4Local

July 2020 - Present

I joined Search4Local in 2019 as a Web Designer and quickly established myself within the team as an expert in my field, continually striving to improve the product offering by increasing awareness of UX principles and developing products to solve our customers' needs.

After a year I was taking on further responsibilities within the team including workload management and training which resulted in me being promoted to Web Design Assistant Manager.

As Assistant Manager my responsibilities increased to include elements of people management and department admin whilst still working primarily on designing websites for our clients. Within my current role I have undergone people management training and coaching sessions to further improve my ability to work in and manage a team.

Alongside my additional responsibilities as Assistant Manager I have been keeping abreast of design trends and principles which has enabled me to completely rebrand the company and drive the improvement of their online presence through redesigning the website, working with the Social Media team to create marketing strategies and even organising and attending the companies first trade show.

#### Responsibilities:

- → Working to a brief to design and build websites for small to medium sized businesses
- → Developing and maintaining additional web based products
- → Managing and the daily web builds work load
- → Studying analytical data to improve our websites and product offering
- → Carrying out design training sessions for junior and trainee designers.

#### Senior Web Designer - Funeral Guide

March 2019 - July 2020

As the sole Web Designer I was responsible for transforming their online presence by rebranding and redesigning the website and creating a new website for Arranger, the company's web application. I also worked on user interface design for the Arranger web application based on research and wireframes created by UX designers whilst working to Material Design principles and guidelines.

#### Responsibilities:

- → Redesigning and maintaining the Funeral Guide website
- → Working on the user experience and interface design for Arranger.com
- → Working with UX researchers to crate designer for the Arranger web application
- → Creating artwork and graphics for advertising on social media
- → Working with print designers to implement new brand styles across all platforms.

#### Middleweight Digital Designer - Equiniti Data

October 2017 - March 2019

Working as a Middleweight Digital Designer within a design department to create marketing materials for big name clients, as well as designing internal collateral for advertising campaigns and digital products.

#### Responsibilities:

- → Following strict brand guidelines to create marketing campaigns for a range of clients including Santander, Legal & General and Tails.com
- → Designing graphics to accompany marketing campaigns
- → Working with HTML and CSS to develop web pages and responsive emails
- → Designing documents for print such as flyers, postcards and booklets
- → Researching and developing to be able to offer the latest HTML email technologies.

#### Junior Digital Designer - Axminster Tools & Machinery

March 2016 - September 2017

Working within a team of four Digital Designers creating email and website marketing materials to appeal to a wide customer base and drive sales.

#### Responsibilities:

- → Working to a brief to create marketing material
- → Building responsive HTML emails to send to customers
- → Designing graphics to accompany marketing campaigns
- → Working with HTML and CSS to develop landing pages.

#### Apprentice Web Designer - Vector 7

July 2014 - March 2016

Working closely with clients to design and develop websites and online marketing materials in order to get them found on search engines for what they do and where they do it.

#### Responsibilities:

- → Designing new websites to a client's brief
- → Building user friendly websites for a range of businesses
- → Improving the look and functionality of existing websites
- → Conducting meetings with new and existing clients Interpreting analytical data to feedback to clients.

#### **Education**

Plymouth College of Art September 2014 - October 2015 BTech Level 3 in Graphic Design

The King's School Ottery St Mary September 2012 - July 2014 A Levels in ICT & Design Technology

The King's School Ottery St Mary September 2010 - June 2012 GCSE's in:

- English
- Maths
- Science
- ICT
- Design Technology
- Geography
- History

## Personal Information

Address:

80 Wilton Way Exeter, Devon EX1 3UR

Contact details: 07903 354 879

jharmer220995@gmail.com

Driving licence: Yes